► Ctrl+Click a word to display verses with related words from the same root.
► Full information for Allah, non-Allah, repeated, and all Quran words
► Updated root database (thanks to brother Yudi Rohmad, Indonesia).
► Easy selection of initialized chapters (الحروف المقطعة) and non-initialized chapters
► Front-Back Symmetry (WordLetters, VerseWords, VerseLetters).
► Display number of verses before and after current verse within its chapter and within the whole Quran
► Calculate the LetterFrequencySum for any user phrase in each verse in all selected chapters
► Visual representation of found matches per chapter using different color shades
► Highlight of values that are divisible by any user-defined divisor
► Support for IndoPak font family (thanks to brother Tariq Mahmood, Pakistan)
► Waw as a word option in any Simplified text mode
► Shadda as a double letter option in any Simplified text mode
► BismAllah chapter prefixes option in any Simplified text mode. BismAllah of surat Al-Fatiha is not a prefix but verse #1
► Multi-select in Word Frequency List sorted in descending order
► Multi-select in Letter Frequency List with immediate sum prime factorization
► Assign DNA symbols (A T C G) to the Arabic alphabet in prime number proportions (Belkacem Meghzouchene, Algeria)
► Find sentences by numbers (words/letters/value)
► Find sentences by letter frequency sum
► Verse translations in all selected languages are displayed at the same time
► Display Original text but use Simplified29 word/letter counts
► Chapter detailed info as you move over each chapter
► Calculate any mathematical including + - * / ^ pi e phi sin cos log ... (in number bases 2 to 36)
► Improved search in emlaaei to find hamza + elf = elf memdooda Thanks to Ali Pouradam
► FindByNumbers words / sentences / verses / chapters by numbers, words, letters, unique letters, value, or their sums
► FindByNumbers word ranges / verse ranges / chapter ranges by sum of numbers, chapters, verses, words, letters, unique letters, value, or their sums
► FindByNumbers supports all comparison operators and MultipleOf N and IndivisibleBy N (with user-defined remainder)
► F1 for Help
► F2 for Bookmarks
► F3/Shift+F3 to navigate forward/backward through search results
► F4 or right-click for Related Words as current selected text or word under mouse pointer
► F5 or right-click for Related Verses as current verse under mouse pointer
► F6 or right-click for Same Text as current selected text or word under mouse pointer
► F7 or right-click for Same Text and Harakat as current selected text or word under mouse pointer
► F8 or right-click for Same Verses containing current verse under mouse pointer
► F9 or right-click for Same Value text as current selected text or verse under mouse pointer
► Play Previous verse and Play Next verse buttons added to mp3 player
► Dynamic keyboard for each text mode with optional harakat inclusion
► Search in current translation or in all currently installed translations
► Search in current text mode or in all text modes in case user enters non-simplified letters in a simplified text mode
► Search by root with multi-root support and +/- include/exclude options
► Find by Letter Frequency Sum supports all comparison operators
► WORDS search supports "-" and "+" at word start to exclude or include words respectively
► Silence between verses from 0.0 to 2.0 times the verse length in 0.1 increments
► Text zoom-in/zoom-out and graph zoom-in/zoom-out
► Full statistics of the word Allah and its derivatives (2816 in total)
► Draw the locations of the word "Allah" in the current selection
► Draw selection letter/word values as square, golden ratios, or spirals
► Direct chapter/verse entry (1, 3-4, 5:55, 3-4:19, 6:19-23, 24:35-27:62) 
► Direct page, station, part, group, half, quarter, bowing, verse, word, letter entry (1, 1-2, ...) 
► Chapter/Verse/Word/Letter distances on text clicks across pages or across search results
► Word meaning and transliteration as mouse moves over words
► Auto-download recitations in any reciter from http://everyayah.com with auto-repeat 2, 3, 5, 7 or unlimited times.
► Auto-download translations from http://tanzil.net
► Auto-detect search language (Arabic or any loaded translation)
► Back/Shift+Back to move backward/forward in browse or find history
► Find History and Browse History (with auto-select chapter range)
► Add, remove, edit and auto-save/auto-load Bookmark notes
► Support for any user defined SimplifiedXX Quran books
► Any-language search in Uthmani, Emlaei, Turkish, Farsi, Urdu, Malay, Indonesian, English, Polish, Japanese, Russian, Chinese, ...

Additional Tools
► QuranLab for investigating the amazing properties of the 114 number of verses per chapter in the Quran
► InitialLetters to form sentences using the 14 Quran's initial letters (Hiroof Muqata3a) and Quran words only
► Prime Calculator with built-in Yafu tool for factoring big numbers with next/previous prime finder
► Prime Calculator with missing parameter calculations for circle/sphere/triangle
► Composites for finding composites with specified number of factors and analyze their types

God bless and protect those who follow His Commandments.

Ali Adams
God >
