► Ctrl+Click a word to display verses with related words from the same root.
► Full statistics of the word Allah and its derivatives (2816 in total)
► Updated root database (thanks to brother Yudi Rohmad, Indonesia).
► Easy selection of initialized chapters (الحروف المقطعة) and non-initialized chapters
► Auto display of 4n+1 Prime = Sum and difference of two squares.
► Auto display of 4n+1 Composite = Difference of two squares in two ways.
► Front-Back Symmetry (WordLetters, VerseWords, VerseLetters).
► Waleed's CPIndexChain System. See QuranCode\Help\114.txt Pattern 619.
► Base-2: valuation system with byte size = word length
Key letters = 1, Others = 0
Initial letters = 1, Others = 0
Solar letters = 1, Lunar letters = 0
Lunar letters = 1, Solar letters = 0
► Base-3: valuation system with byte size = word length
KeyInitials = 2, KeyNonInitials = 1, Others = 0
► Base-4: valuation system with byte size = word length
InitialsSolar: InitialSolar=3, Initial=2, Solar=1, Others=0
InitialsLunar: InitialLunar=3, Initial=2, Lunar=1, Others=0
SolarInitials: SolarInitial=3, Solar=2, Initial=1, Others=0
LunarInitials: LunarInitial=3, Lunar=2, Initial=1, Others=0
The inspiration comes from Abdulsalam Al-Mayahi who suggested that:
Quran 35:1 "In the Name of Allah, the All-beneficent, the All-merciful. All praise belongs to Allah, originator of the heavens and the earth, maker of the angels His Messengers, possessing wings, two, three or four of them. He adds to the creation whatever He wishes. Indeed Allah has power over all things."
may mean base-2, base-3 and base-4 number systems respectively :)
► Full information for Allah, non-Allah, repeated, and all Quran words
► Display number of verses before and after current verse within its chapter and within the whole Quran
► C, V, C+V, C-V classification into Odd/Even and Prime/Composite for current chapters
► C, V, C+V, C-V classification into Odd/Even and Prime/Composite for current verses
► Calculate the LetterFrequencySum for any user phrase in each verse in all selected chapters
► Visual representation of found matches per chapter using different color shades
► Highlight of values that are divisible by any user-defined divisor
► Support for IndoPak font family (thanks to brother Tariq Mahmood, Pakistan)
► Waw as a word option in any Simplified text mode
► Shadda as a double letter option in any Simplified text mode
► BismAllah chapter prefixes option in any Simplified text mode. BismAllah of surat Al-Fatiha is not a prefix but verse #1
► Multi-select in Word Frequency List sorted in descending order
► Multi-select in Letter Frequency List with immediate sum prime factorization
► Assign DNA symbols (A T C G) to the Arabic alphabet in prime number proportions (Belkacem Meghzouchene, Algeria)
► Golden ratio verse colorization in all text modes at letter/word/sentence levels with both 1 + 0.618 and 0.618 + 1 directions
► Find sentences by numbers (words/letters/value)
► Find sentences by letter frequency sum
► Verse translations in all selected languages are displayed at the same time
► Dynamic letter scope to build numerology system from selected text/selection/Book
► Display Original text but use Simplified29 word/letter counts
► Chapter detailed info as you move over each chapter
► Active hyperlink words as you move over words and click to take you to all verses with words of the same root.
► Calculate any mathematical including + - * / ^ pi e phi sin cos log ... (in number bases 2 to 36)
► Improved search in emlaaei to find hamza + elf = elf memdooda Thanks to Ali Pouradam
► FindByNumbers words / sentences / verses / chapters by numbers, words, letters, unique letters, value, or their sums
► FindByNumbers word ranges / verse ranges / chapter ranges by sum of numbers, chapters, verses, words, letters, unique letters, value, or their sums
► FindByNumbers word sets / verse sets / chapter sets by sum of numbers, chapters, verses, words, letters, unique letters, value, or their sums
► FindByNumbers supports all comparison operators and MultipleOf N and IndivisibleBy N (with user-defined remainder)
► F1 for Help
► F2 for Bookmarks
► F3/Shift+F3 to navigate forward/backward through search results
► F4 or right-click for Related Words as current selected text or word under mouse pointer
► F5 or right-click for Related Verses as current verse under mouse pointer
► F6 or right-click for Same Text as current selected text or word under mouse pointer
► F7 or right-click for Same Text and Harakat as current selected text or word under mouse pointer
► F8 or right-click for Same Verses containing current verse under mouse pointer
► F9 or right-click for Same Value text as current selected text or verse under mouse pointer
► Play Previous verse and Play Next verse buttons added to mp3 player
► Dynamic keyboard for each text mode with optional harakat inclusion
► Optional addition of L, W, V, C, ∆L, ∆W, ∆V, ∆C to letter value
► Optional addition of W, V, C, ∆W, ∆V, ∆C to word value
► Optional addition of V, C, ∆V, ∆C to verse value
► Optional addition of C to chapter value
► Search in current translation or in all currently installed translations
► Search in current text mode or in all text modes in case user enters non-simplified letters in a simplified text mode
► Search by root with multi-root support and +/- include/exclude options
► Find by Letter Frequency Sum supports all comparison operators
► WORDS search supports "-" and "+" at word start to exclude or include words respectively
► Silence between verses from 0.0 to 2.0 times the verse length in 0.1 increments
► Draw the locations of the word "Allah" in the current selection
► Draw selection letter/word values as square, golden ratios, or spirals
► Sort chapters by number, name, revelation, verses, words, letters, or value
► Direct chapter/verse entry (1, 3-4, 5:55, 3-4:19, 6:19-23, 24:35-27:62) 
► Direct page, station, part, group, half, quarter, bowing, verse, word, letter entry (1, 1-2, ...) 
► Word grammar in Arabic and English adapted from http://corpus.quran.com
► Chapter/Verse/Word/Letter distances on text clicks across pages or across search results
► Word meaning and transliteration as mouse moves over words
► Auto-download recitations in any reciter from http://everyayah.com with auto-repeat 2, 3, 5, 7 or unlimited times.
► Auto-download translations from http://tanzil.net
► Auto-detect search language (Arabic or any loaded translation)
► Back/Shift+Back to move backward/forward in browse or find history
► Find History and Browse History (with auto-select chapter range)
► Add, remove, edit and auto-save/auto-load Bookmark notes
► Support for base 2-36 number systems (to study base-19)
► Support for any user defined SimplifiedXX Quran books
► Any-language search in Uthmani, Emlaei, Turkish, Farsi, Urdu, Malay, Indonesian, English, Polish, Japanese, Russian, Chinese, ...

Additional Tools
► QuranLab for investigating the amazing properties of the 114 number of verses per chapter in the Quran
► InitialLetters to form sentences using the 14 Quran's initial letters (Hiroof Muqata3a) and Quran words only
► Prime Calculator with built-in Yafu tool for factoring big numbers with next/previous prime finder
► Prime Calculator with missing parameter calculations for circle/sphere/triangle
► Composites for finding composites with specified number of factors and analyze their types

God bless and protect those who follow His Commandments.

Ali Adams
God >
